Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine.
我是Katherine。
And as you probably noticed on our website, this is one of many different parts of a series
你可能已经在我们网站上注意到了，这是系列节目中的一部分，
all about having an interview in English.
全部关于用英语进行面试。
This is a job interview and at this point we're at about part 7.
这是一场求职面试，现在我们大概进行到第七部分了。
That's right.
没错。
So today what we're going to talk about is the key question whenever you're having a
所以今天我们要讨论的是，在求职面试中一个关键问题，
job interview is they ask you to describe your key strengths.
就是他们让你描述你的主要优势。
And this is our word for vocabulary preview today so let's take a look at it.
这就是我们今天词汇预览的单词，让我们来看看。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so you might have heard the word strength before.
好的，你可能以前听过strength这个词。
This is something that you're good at.
这是指你擅长的事情。
And so key strength or key strengths, plural, would be things that you think are most important
所以key strength或key strengths（复数）指的是你认为自己最重要的方面，
about you as far as the things that you do well.
就你做得好的事情而言。
That's right.
没错。
So as we mentioned, your boss or your potential boss might ask you to describe your key strengths.
所以正如我们提到的，你的老板或潜在老板可能会让你描述你的主要优势。
So you're going to mention a lot of adjectives, positive adjectives saying how good of a worker
你会用到很多形容词，积极的形容词，来说明你是一个多么好的员工。
you are.
你有多优秀。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue.
那我们不如来听听对话吧。
Let's see what Rebecca has to say about her key strengths and we'll look at those in a
让我们听听丽贝卡如何描述她的主要优势，稍后我们会仔细分析这些。
little bit.
稍后。
Okay, Rebecca.
好的，丽贝卡。
Now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background but what about you
现在你已经让我了解了你的工作和学术背景，但作为一个人呢？
as a person?
作为一个人呢？
How would you describe your key strengths?
你会如何描述你的主要优势？
Well Mr. Parsons, as I mentioned before, I'm someone who needs new challenges.
嗯，帕森斯先生，正如我之前提到的，我是一个需要新挑战的人。
I'm really focused and hardworking.
我非常专注且勤奋。
I think my academic results prove this.
我认为我的学术成绩证明了这一点。
Yes, true.
是的，确实如此。
But how about other personal qualities?
但其他个人品质呢？
Well I believe I'm a good team player but I can also work well independently.
嗯，我相信我是一个好的团队合作者，但也能独立工作得很好。
I'm very enthusiastic and well, I hope my colleagues would agree, I'm fun to work with.
我非常热情，而且，我希望我的同事们会同意，和我一起工作很有趣。
What would you say is your most positive quality?
你认为你最积极的品质是什么？
That's a tough question but I would have to say my passion.
这是个棘手的问题，但我必须说是我的热情。
I'm really passionate about journalism and passionate about my career.
我对新闻业充满热情，对我的职业也充满热情。
All right so she obviously has a lot of good key strengths.
好吧，显然她有很多好的主要优势。
Why don't we analyze a couple of those on Language Takeaway.
我们不如在“语言要点”环节分析其中几个。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So one of the first things that Rebecca mentions is that she's really focused.
所以丽贝卡提到的第一件事就是她非常专注。
Okay, so this word focused, what does this mean?
好的，所以这个词 focused，它是什么意思？
All right, so if a person is focused, basically you're saying that you concentrate on your
好吧，如果一个人是 focused，基本上就是说你专注于你的
work.
工作。
That's right and someone who's focused might be very good in a noisy office or in a place
没错，一个专注的人可能在嘈杂的办公室或像你说的那样充满干扰的地方表现很好，
that is full of distractions like you said because they don't stop their work and think
因为他们不会停下工作去思考
about the noise or move around or go talk to people.
噪音，或者四处走动、找人聊天。
Someone who is focused just sits down and can do a lot of work all at once.
一个专注的人就是坐下来，能一下子完成很多工作。
That's right, so she describes herself as focused and hardworking.
没错，所以她形容自己专注且勤奋。
So hardworking means basically what it sounds like, that someone works very hard.
所以 hardworking 基本上就是字面意思，指一个人工作非常努力。
That means they put in a lot of hours, they get their work done, they're really, really
这意味着他们投入很多时间，完成工作，非常非常
dependable.
可靠。
That's right, so as you can see we use the word hardworking together.
没错，所以你看，我们经常把 hardworking 这个词连在一起用。
So if you work hard, you don't say I work hard.
所以如果你工作努力，你不会说“我工作努力”。
You can say that but if you want to use it as an adjective, you say I am hardworking.
你可以那么说，但如果你想把它用作形容词，你会说“我是勤奋的”。
The opposite of course would be lazy.
当然，反义词是懒惰。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we're focused, we're hardworking and she also said that she is a good team
好的，所以我们专注、勤奋，她还说她是一个好的团队
player.
成员。
Okay, this is a really key phrase here because it's something that employers, so people who
好的，这是一个非常关键的短语，因为雇主，也就是那些
are hiring new staff like to look out for because most jobs you don't work alone.
招聘新员工的人，喜欢留意这一点，因为大多数工作都不是独自完成的。
You work with other people and so a team player is someone who works well in a group or works
你和其他人一起工作，所以团队合作者是指能在团队中或与他人良好协作的人。
well with others.
嗯，和别人相处。
That's right, so a team player, everyone wants to have a good team player working for their
没错，所以“有团队精神的人”是大家都希望拥有的好员工。
team, for their company.
团队，为了他们的公司。
And apart from being a good team player, you also want to be enthusiastic.
除了要具备良好的团队合作精神，你还得充满热情。
That's right, so this means that you are interested in what you do, you are excited about it.
没错，所以这意味着你对自己所做的事情感兴趣，并且充满热情。
It's not like oh God, I have to do this report.
这不像“哦天哪，我得写这份报告”那样。
It's like oh wow, I get to do this report, I'm enthusiastic, I'm really interested, I'm
就像“哦，哇，我要做这份报告，我很热情，我真的很感兴趣，我——”
going to put a lot of energy into it.
我会投入很多精力去做这件事。
That's right.
没错。
So being an enthusiastic person not only can be about working, you can be enthusiastic
所以，做一个充满热情的人不仅仅体现在工作上，你可以在生活中也充满热情。
about anything, about painting your house, about going on a trip.
任何事情，比如粉刷房子、出去旅行。
Exactly, enthusiastic.
没错，热情。
Alright and our last word for language, takeaway is also a good quality to have if you are
好的，我们最后一个关于语言的词是“takeaway”，如果你……，这也是一个很好的品质。
passionate about what you do or what you're doing.
对你所做的事情充满热情。
So someone who is passionate about something really, really likes that thing.
所以，一个对某事充满热情的人，就是真的、真的非常喜欢那件事。
That means that they love to do it or love to see it.
这意味着他们喜欢做这件事，或者喜欢看这件事。
Passion is the opposite of not interested.
激情就是不感兴趣的反面。
So you're really, really emotional and excited and interested in something.
所以你对某件事真的非常情绪化、兴奋且感兴趣。
That's right, so you are passionate about something.
没错，所以你对某件事充满热情。
It comes from the noun passion, so you have a passion for painting, maybe you love to
它来自名词 passion，所以你对绘画有热情，也许你热爱
paint.
绘画。
So you're very passionate about painting.
所以你对绘画充满热情。
So a lot of great adjectives there to describe yourself in a good way.
所以有很多很好的形容词可以用积极的方式描述自己。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不听一遍我们的对话，然后回来进行流利度训练。
Okay Rebecca, now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background,
好的，Rebecca，现在你对你的工作和学术背景有了很好的了解，
but what about you as a person?
但你作为一个人呢？
How would you describe your key strengths?
你会如何描述你的主要优势？
Well Mr. Parsons, as I mentioned before, I'm someone who needs new challenges.
嗯，Parsons先生，正如我之前提到的，我是一个需要新挑战的人。
I'm really focused and hardworking.
我非常专注和勤奋。
I think my academic results prove this.
我认为我的学术成绩证明了这一点。
Yes, true.
是的，没错。
But how about other personal qualities?
但其他个人品质呢？
Well I believe I'm a good team player, but I can also work well independently.
嗯，我相信我是一个好的团队合作者，但我也能独立工作得很好。
I'm very enthusiastic and well, I hope my colleagues would agree, I'm fun to work with.
我非常热情，而且，我希望我的同事们会同意，和我一起工作很有趣。
What would you say is your most positive quality?
你认为你最积极的品质是什么？
Hmm, that's a tough question.
嗯，这是个棘手的问题。
But I would have to say my passion.
但我必须说是我的热情。
I'm really passionate about journalism and passionate about my career.
我对新闻业充满热情，对我的职业也充满热情。
Alright so on Fluency Builder today we've picked out three key phrases.
好的，在今天的流利度训练中，我们挑选了三个关键短语。
Let's take a look at the first one.
让我们看看第一个。
When Rebecca said, I'm someone who needs new challenges.
当Rebecca说，我是一个需要新挑战的人。
Okay so this structure, I'm someone who, is something that you hear a lot of and you can
好的，这个结构“我是一个……的人”，你经常听到，而且你可以
actually fill in the end of that sentence with a number of different phrases.
用许多不同的短语来填充这个句子的结尾。
So in here we heard, I'm someone who needs new challenges.
所以在这里我们听到，我是一个需要新挑战的人。
We could also say, I'm someone who needs structure.
我们也可以说，我是一个需要结构的人。
Alright so we can also change the verb right from needs to, I'm someone who likes a challenge.
好的，我们也可以把动词从“需要”改成，我是一个喜欢挑战的人。
Or maybe Tracy is someone who requires a lot of attention.
或者也许Tracy是一个需要很多关注的人。
Right, so this is a way to introduce a characteristic of yourself.
对，所以这是一种介绍自己特点的方式。
So you're telling people something about yourself.
所以你是在告诉别人关于你自己的事情。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So moving on, we also saw that Rebecca said that she is fun to work with.
继续，我们还看到Rebecca说她是一个一起工作很有趣的人。
I'm fun to work with.
和我一起工作很有趣。
Okay so let's just treat this like a little fixed phrase.
好的，我们就把这当作一个固定短语。
We say this about people all the time.
我们经常这样评价别人。
He's fun to work with, she's fun to work with, or this group is really fun to work with.
和他一起工作很有趣，和她一起工作很有趣，或者这个团队一起工作真的很有趣。
They're all really fun to work with.
他们都很有趣，一起工作。
So that means that it's not serious, that you really enjoy doing it.
所以这意味着不严肃，你真的很享受做这件事。
So it's a little fixed phrase that you can use to say that it's nice to work with Rebecca
所以这是一个固定短语，你可以用它来说和Rebecca一起工作很好，
or that she's very, not serious, not a mean person.
或者她非常不严肃，不是一个刻薄的人。
That's right.
没错。
And finally we have a phrase at the end, Rebecca hears a question she thinks is very difficult,
最后我们有一个短语，Rebecca听到一个她觉得很难的问题，
she calls it a tough question.
她称之为一个棘手的问题。
And so a tough question is something that is very hard to answer.
所以一个棘手的问题就是很难回答的事情。
That's right, she says, hmm, that's a tough question.
没错，她说，嗯，这是个棘手的问题。
So she's basically acknowledging the fact that the question is difficult, a tough question.
所以她基本上是在承认这个问题很难，一个棘手的问题。
Now we can combine this word tough with other things.
现在我们可以把这个词“棘手”和其他东西组合起来。
That's right, you can say it's a tough situation, that means it's a hard situation to handle.
没错，你可以说这是一个棘手的情况，意思是这是一个很难处理的情况。
You could also say he's having a tough time, that means that right now in his life there
你也可以说他正在经历一段艰难时期，意思是现在在他的生活中
are many things that are difficult for him.
有很多事情对他来说很困难。
And so tough means difficult or hard or unpleasant.
所以“棘手”意味着困难或艰难或不愉快。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a lot of good stuff coming from Rebecca, mentioning all the positive things about her.
所以Rebecca说了很多好东西，提到了她所有的积极方面。
Why don't we listen to her dialogue one last time.
我们为什么不最后听一遍她的对话。
Okay Rebecca, now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background, but
好的，Rebecca，现在你对你的工作和学术背景有了很好的了解，
what about you as a person?
但你作为一个人呢？
How would you describe your key strengths?
你会如何描述你的主要优势？
Well Mr. Parsons, as I mentioned before, I'm someone who needs new challenges.
嗯，Parsons先生，正如我之前提到的，我是一个需要新挑战的人。
I'm really focused and hardworking.
我非常专注和勤奋。
I think my academic results prove this.
我认为我的学术成绩证明了这一点。
Yes, true.
是的，没错。
But how about other personal qualities?
但其他个人品质呢？
Well I believe I'm a good team player, but I can also work well independently.
嗯，我相信我是一个好的团队合作者，但我也能独立工作得很好。
I'm very enthusiastic and, well, I hope my colleagues would agree, I'm fun to work with.
我非常热情，而且，我希望我的同事们会同意，和我一起工作很有趣。
What would you say is your most positive quality?
你认为你最积极的品质是什么？
Hmm, that's a tough question.
嗯，这是个棘手的问题。
But I would have to say my passion.
但我必须说是我的热情。
I'm really passionate about journalism and passionate about my career.
我对新闻业充满热情，对我的职业也充满热情。
Alright so talking about key strengths, I think it's always difficult to talk about
好的，谈论主要优势，我认为总是很难谈论
yourself and still sound a little bit humble, right, to not sound arrogant like saying I'm
自己，同时听起来还有点谦虚，对吧，不要听起来傲慢，比如说我是
the best.
最好的。
Right, well that's the key here I think.
对，我认为这就是关键。
You want to say really good things about yourself because you're a salesperson and you're selling
你想说关于自己的好话，因为你是一个销售员，你在推销
your personality.
你的个性。
But at the same time you don't want to sound like a jerk.
但同时你不想听起来像个混蛋。
Like I'm the best, I'm so smart, I'm so clever.
比如我是最好的，我太聪明了，我太聪明了。
That's a little bit off-putting, it makes people uncomfortable.
这有点让人反感，让人不舒服。
So I think the trick is a balance.
所以我认为诀窍是平衡。
And I guess if you use words such as this, like you know, I'm focused, I'm hardworking,
我想如果你用这样的词，比如你知道，我专注，我勤奋，
I'm independent, I have a passion for this.
我独立，我对这个有热情。
It makes you sound like you're a really good worker but you're not arrogant, you're not
这让你听起来像是个很棒的员工，但又不显得傲慢，你不会
saying oh well, you know, I'm the best of what I do or something like that.
说“哦，你知道，我是我这一行最棒的”之类的话。
Right, so you're basically saying these are my skills but obviously I'm not the only person
对，所以你基本上是在说这些是我的技能，但显然我不是唯一
who has these great skills.
拥有这些出色技能的人。
That's right.
没错。
Okay so that's all the time we have for today.
好了，这就是我们今天的所有内容。
Be sure to join us next week.
请务必在下周加入我们。
We're also going to have kind of part two of this when we talk about our weaknesses.
我们还会有一个第二部分，讨论我们的弱点。
So this time we talked about our strengths, then we'll talk about weaknesses.
所以这次我们谈了我们的优势，然后我们会谈弱点。
That's right.
没错。
So we hope that you will check out our website EnglishPod.com.
所以我们希望你会访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
If you have questions or comments, leave them there for us and we'll be in touch very soon.
如果你有问题或评论，请留在那里，我们会很快联系你。
All right, we'll see you guys there.
好了，我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Oh yeah!
哦耶！